Robert Whittaker

Junior Front-end Developer | Music & Video Producer | Music Typesetter

Mobile: 07930592148 | Email: rbrwhittaker@yahoo.com

SUMMARY

I am a self-taught front-end developer focussing on writing clean, efficient, legible code. I'm confident in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, plus modern libraries and frameworks. Am passionate about developing user-friendly front-end solutions and am full of creative ideas with a willingness to experiment. For the past 6 months I've been studying front-end development through online courses with the guidance of a mentor. I am also experienced in production software including Cubase, Pro Tools, Logic Pro, Sibelius, Premiere Pro and Photoshop.

Languages

React

• JavaScript ES6

•HTML/CSS

FRONT-END EXPERIENCE

/////// Portfolio can be found at – https://robwhittaker94.github.io ////////

The complete JavaScript course 2020 – Jonas Schmedtmann

Modern React with Redux - Stephen Grider

The Complete Node.JS Developer Course (3rd edn) – Andrew Meade

Completed: March 2022 Completed: March 2022

Expected completion: May 2022

Projects built

Portfolio (Linktree inspired landing page)

Wordle Clone

"Should I wear my shorts today?" (Weather app)

'Matrix' Digital Rain (landing page)

Dice Game

Completed April 2022 Completed: January 2022

Expected completion: May 2022 Completed: February 2022 Completed: February 2022

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Royal Mail - 2020-2021

During the COVID-19 pandemic, as the live music industry was on pause, I was a Postman for Newport, South Wales.

Freelance Work - 2015-2020

- Video Producer: Working one-to-one with clients to produce promo/lyric videos for digital platforms using Adobe Premier Pro and After Effects.
- Music Producer/Sound Engineer: Recording studios Rockfield Studios (Monmouth), Cardiff University School of Music, Green Rooms (Pontypridd), Unit 13 (Tredegar). Software: Pro Tools and Logic Pro.
- Music Editing/Typesetting: Setting music examples for publication in academic books and journal articles. Software: Sibelius Music Notation.
- Composer & Performer: EP of original songs plus recorded singles with various artists incl. session work. Guitarist/vocalist/cellist– live concert performances around Wales/UK. Software: Cubase (composing)
- · Lower Machen Festival: Sound and lighting engineer, stage construction, front of house staff.
- TV/Film extra: Casualty (BBC One drama series), How I live now (2013, dir. Kevin Macdonald)

EDUCATION

BSc (Hons) Creative Industries (Popular Music Technology)

University of South Wales 2012-2015